To think the Guild would send
me a challenge request.
ギルドが僕に挑戦状とはねェ
This'll stave off my boredom a little.
これで少しは退屈が紛れる
To Edogawa Rampo
Invitation for a Detective Game
Though I suspect it's a trap.
罠だと思うけどねぇ
Welcome, Rampo-kun
A is B
A is not B
Fill in A and B so that both
hold true, and enter the room.
I guess he wants you to fill in the blanks.
空欄を埋めろってことみたいだね
まあ妾にゃさっぱりだけど
Not that I have any idea.
Yosano-san, do you have a pen?
与謝野さん　ペン貸して
Are you the mastermind who
thought to challenge me?
君かい　僕に挑戦するという偉い人は
Chief Architect
of the Guild
E. A. Poe
Ability: Black Cat in
the Rue Morgue
久し振りだな　乱歩君よ
It's been a long time, Rampo-kun.
Were you been able to solve
the riddle at the entrance?
表の問題は解いていただけたかな
This sentence is five words.
This sentence is not five words.
I'd expect no less from my
worthy opponent, Rampo-kun.
流石は乱歩君　我が倒すべき宿敵である
Now, it's my turn to ask a question.
次は僕が質問する番だ
Who are you?
あんた誰
You don't remember me?
我輩を覚えていない
君との勝負の為だけに　わざわざギルドの遠征に加わったのに
I joined the Guild just so
that I could challenge you.
我輩はポオ
I am Poe!
探偵にして知の巨人
Detective and master of intellect.
六年前　君との勝負に敗れた者である
You defeated me six years ago.
Your rant's making me sleepy.
眠たい話ならいいや　帰る
I'm leaving.
This is a detective game!
推理遊戯である
Read this detective novel I've prepared for you,
and determine the identity of the serial killer.
我輩の用意したこの推理小説を読み
連続殺人の真相を的中させることである
マイナス一点
One point docked.
You wouldn't have become a detective
if you were content with novels.
小説で事足りるなら　探偵になってない
I expected that reply.
その返答は想定済みである
How about, if you win,
I tell you the Guild's weakness?
もし吾輩に勝ったら…
ギルドの弱点を教えるとしたらどうだろうか？
How to capture the Guild base,
Moby Dick, the floating fortress.
ギルドの拠点　空中要塞「白鯨」の攻略法である
One point granted.
プラス一点
But why such a silly challenge?
けど　なんでそんな莫迦げた勝負を
ギルドの作戦など野蛮なばかりで退屈極まりない
The Guild's operations are barbaric
and unbearably boring.
The only thing humanity
ought to have interest in
この世で人類が唯一驚嘆し刮目すべきは…
is your gift, Ultra Deduction.
君の異能力　「超推理」のみ
Am I wrong?
違うかね
Five points granted.
プラス五点
I'm game.
やろう
The story begins like this:
物語の始まりはこうだ
One night, once upon a time,
ある時代のある夜　数人の滞在客が吹雪で洋館に閉じ込められた
a band of visitors were trapped
in a mansion due to a snowstorm.
On the night of their stay,
the protagonist, a private detective,
やむなく宿泊した夜
私立探偵である主人公は
ある部屋からの奇妙な物音で目を覚ます
is awakened by a strange noise
coming from one of the rooms.
This is my ability.
これが我輩の異能力だ
The ability to suck a reader into a novel.
読者を小説の中に引きずり込む能力
Welcome to the house of tragedies.
惨劇の館へようこそ
The protagonist opens the door
with a key only he possesses.
主人公は保管されていた合鍵で部屋のドアを開ける
What he saw there...
そこで見たものは…
A victim.
被害者
The two windows were sealed, and no one
could have entered or left the room.
二つの窓ははめ殺しで　出入り不可能
Two doors, and a matching key.
ドアが二つ
そして　合鍵はここに
I don't have my glasses.
眼鏡がない
死んでるのか
Is he dead?
Stand back.
下がってな　妾は医者だよ
I'm a doctor.
しっかりしな
Hang in there.
ド…ドアに…
Th-The door...
あいつはこれを連続殺人と云った
He said it was a serial killer.
Which means we need to find the
murderer, or we'll be killed, too.
犯人を見つけないと　いずれ僕達も殺されるってことか
What a pain in the ass, that ability.
まったく　とんだ異能力だよ
死体も血も悍ましいほど現実的だ
The corpse and the blood are
disgustingly convincing.
おまけに妾の異能力「君死給勿」が発動しないときた
Not to mention my ability,
Thou Shalt Not Die, doesn't work here.
The victim is the caretaker of this mansion.
被害者はこの洋館の管理人　死因は出血性ショック死
Cause of death is hemorrhagic shock.
凶器と指紋はなし　つまり…
No weapon, no fingerprints.
Which means...
It's a textbook impossible murder.
典型的な不可能犯罪だね
A locked room with no way out.
出口のない密室　明らかに他殺の被害者
Clearly the victim of a murder.
犯人はどうやって密室から逃げたのか？
How did the killer leave the room?
随分と歯切れが悪いじゃないか
You're having a surprisingly
hard time with this.
いつもの　やんないのかい
Aren't you going to do your usual thing?
眼鏡がない
I don't have my glasses.
They were special glasses
that the boss gave me.
あれは社長から下賜された特別な眼鏡で　僕の異能力発動に必須だ
I need them to start my special ability.
Also, your healing ability
wouldn't work on that dying man.
それに　与謝野さんも瀕死の相手に治癒異能力が発動しなかった
つまりこの世界では僕の「超推理」も発動しない
In other words, in this world,
my Ultra Deduction won't work either.
So that's how it's going to be.
そういう話になるのかい
Rampo-san doesn't realize that he's an
ordinary person without any special abilities.
乱歩さんは異能力を持たない一般人だってこと　本人は知らないんだよね
Then how about we investigate
carefully and reason our way out?
それならいっそ地道に調査して推理するってのはどうだ？
Too much work.
面倒　地味　退屈
Lame.
Boring.
Investigating and making inquiries is the
work of detectives, not master detectives.
コツコツ調べ物とか聞き込みとかは
探偵の仕事で　名探偵の仕事ではなーい
Kurosaki
Convicted of Blackmail
俺は殺していない
I didn't kill him.
Ukai
Trashy Magazine
Reporter
It wasn't me.
私はやってない　本当だ
I swear.
Reida
Student
I didn't kill him.
僕は殺していません
Proprietor
Well-Bred
Young Lady,
Traveling Alone
何故私が疑われなければならないの
Why am I under suspicion?
Do you have an alibi for the
time of the murder?
事件当時の不在証明は
I was sleeping in my room.
部屋で一人寝ていた
炊事室で暖炉用の薪を割っておりました
I was chopping firewood in the kitchen.
I was looking up the curse of the mansion,
Pluto, the one-eyed cat, in the study.
この館の怨念　片眼の猫「pluto」について書庫で調べ物を
Why do I have to explain myself?
何故私が弁解など
高が施設付きの館医のくせに　何様の心算
You're just a doctor.
Who do you think you are?
お…思い出しました
I remember now.
もう少し私に似合う服はないかと替えの服を頂きに管理人さんの処へ
I went to the caretaker's room to see if
I could find some clothes that fit me better.
矢張りあの部屋に書かれた片眼猫の怨念では
Perhaps it was the curse of the one-eyed
cat depicted in the painting in the room?
これは糸を使ったトリックですよ
This is a trick involving strings.
The key to the locked room was
inside the victim's clothes.
密室の鍵は被害者の服の中にありました
The single matching key was
never used until right before.
唯一の合鍵も直前まで使われていません
The suspect killed the caretaker, took the key,
and locked the room from outside.
犯人は管理人を殺し　鍵を奪って　部屋の外に出てから施錠
その後　天蚕糸を使ってドアの隙間から鍵をポケットに戻す
Later, the suspect used a string to return
the key to the pocket under the door.
He cut the string, collected it,
and disposed of it.
天蚕糸は切って回収し処分した
How's that, detective?
どうです　探偵さん
What are you, stupid?
莫迦か　君は
No, rhetorical questions are rude.
いや　疑問形は失礼だな
You're stupid.
莫迦だ　君は
The key is too thick to fit under the door.
ドアの隙間は鍵より細かったし
鍵は仰向けに倒れてる死体の尻ポケットに入ってた
The corpse was on its back,
and the key was in his hip pocket.
それくらい一目見れば判るだろう
You could have figured that out right away.
で…では　犯人は窓の鉄格子を外し　外に出た後
Th-Then the murderer removed
the iron bars on the window, left the room,
used tools to return the
iron bars, and escaped.
工具で格子を元に戻して脱出を
窓の外は景色も見えないほどの吹雪なのに
Even though it's snowing so hard
outside that you can't even see?
It wasn't wet near the window.
窓の周囲は雪で濡れてもいなかったけど
絶好調じゃないか　乱歩さん
You're killing it, Rampo-san.
違う
No!
僕は…
I just...
You must have had suspicions.
薄々気づいてたんだろ
Your abilities as a detective...
乱歩さんの推理力は…
僕は異能力者だ
I'm gifted.
だからこの世界では何の力もない
But my gift has no value in this world.
It was the boss who gave me those glasses!
あの眼鏡をくれたのは社長だ
社長が僕に嘘を吐いてるっていうのか
Do you mean to tell me that
the boss is lying to me?
いいや　そんな筈ないよね
No.
You're right, of course.
Not even you will ever solve
this mystery, Rampo-kun.
乱歩君でもこの謎は絶対に解けぬ
これは対乱歩君用に書かれた極めて変則的な高位推理小説
It's a supremely unusual meta-mystery
written specifically for you.
一度小説に入ったが最後　犯人も犯行方法も絶対に判らぬ
Once you're in the book, it's over.
You'll never figure out the
killer or how they did it.
This isn't a challenge.
これは勝負ではない
復讐である
This is revenge.
You may have forgotten, but I never will.
君は忘れても　我輩は決して忘れない
あの日　乱歩君との頭脳勝負に敗れ
That day, when you defeated me in a battle of wits,
I lost all reason to show my face to anyone.
他者と関わる理由を凡て失った我輩の精神は
My mind wandered in an endless, dark room.
永く暗き部屋を彷徨った
But I realized I can live on.
だが気づいたのだ　生きてもよいのだと
乱歩君が持つ両手いっぱいの栄光と賛辞
If I only had the plentiful glory and
praise you do, I could...
それさえあれば　我輩は…
So I will take them from you.
だから奪うのだ
Even if that means I have to burn you alive.
仮令君を焼き尽くしたとしても
This is a serial murder.
こいつは連続殺人事件
この密室にわざと一人きりになれば　犯人はきっと殺しに来る
If I deliberately stay in a locked room by myself,
the killer will come to kill me.
さあ　どっからでも来な
Now, come get me.
Yosano-san...
与謝野さん…
Sorry.
悪ぃ　しくじっちまったよ
I messed up.
犯人は…見えなかった
I couldn't see the murderer.
No.
いい　喋るな
Don't talk.
I can't figure it out.
妾にゃお手上げだ
But it's a piece of cake for the
world's best detective.
けど　世界最高の名探偵なら　楽勝さ…
The Armed Detective Agency was established
solely to make use of your gift, after all.
何せ武装探偵社は　乱歩さんの才能を活かす為だけに設立された組織だからね
妾を探偵社に誘ってくれたこと…
I'm still grateful that I was
invited to the Agency.
今も感謝して…
One down!
先ずは一人
So long as you don't solve the mystery,
you'll never return into the real world.
真実を暴かぬ限り　現実世界には戻れぬ
永遠に我が小説世界を彷徨うがいい
Spend all eternity wandering
through my novel world!
戻った
We're back.
ば…莫迦な
I-Impossible.
You couldn't have solved that mystery!
あの謎が解ける筈がない
Well, it was quite stimulating.
いや　中々刺激的だったよ
You made only one mistake...
君のミスは一つだけ
僕に勝負を挑んだことだ
Challenging me.
Y-You figured out who the killer was?
は…犯人が判ったのであるか
Of course.
勿論
犯人は…
The murderer...
was me.
僕だ
The locked room trick had
nothing to do with it.
密室トリックも何もない
The protagonist killed the victim, and the author
deliberately omitted that part of the narration.
主人公が被害者を殺し　作者が意図的にその描写を省いたんだ
But the innovation in this gimmick
was the mechanism by which
ただ今回のトリックで革新的だったのは
僕が小説に入った瞬間　犯人が消滅してしまう仕組みだ
the murderer vanishes the
moment I enter the novel.
No matter how desperately I search,
the murderer no longer exists.
いくら血眼で捜しても　犯人はもうどこにもいないわけだからね
How did you find the truth?
何故真相が判った
You went too far with
the locked-room murder.
密室殺人　あれはやり過ぎだよ
It's one thing if you were going
to lay the blame on someone else,
誰かに容疑を向けるならともかく
but the murderer had no reason to
make such an inescapable room.
密室まで作る理由が犯人にはないもの
So, I figured, the murderer and
the author must be in cahoots.
で　気づいた
犯人と作者は共犯だって
The proof was in the glove left under
the brick wall, used for the murder.
証拠は煉瓦壁の下の隙間に捨ててあった殺害用の手袋
The one the victim pointed
at right before he died.
被害者が死ぬ間際に指差したものだ
し…しかし二番目の犯行は
B-But the second murder...
The murderer had already
vanished by then, had he not?
犯人は既に消滅していたのであろう
そっちは更に単純
That one's even simpler.
You just used an automatic machine.
そういう自動機械を使っただけ
室内の磁場を局所操作して　金属を被害者に叩きつけた
You manipulated the magnetism in the room
and threw a metal object at the victim.
そんなものが可能だと思うのであるか
Do you think that's even possible?
Anything goes.
何だってアリだ
That's the second misdirection, after all.
それが二つ目の誤誘導だからね
ヒントはそこらじゅうにあった
There were hints everywhere.
The suspiciously state-of-the-art
medical tools.
妙に最新鋭の医療器具
The characters, wearing clothes provided by
the mansion rather than clothes of their own.
自前じゃなく　館所有の服を着た登場人物
The story is set in 2050.
この小説の舞台は二〇五〇年だ
The mansion is actually a rest house
attached to a massive, tall space elevator.
天空へと続く巨大な軌道エレベーターに付設された休憩施設
それがあの館の正体だ
As complicated as a detective novel may get,
まぁ　どんなに難解な推理小説も
once you figure out the author's ulterior
motives, you've figured out half of it.
作者の悪意が読めた時点で　半分は解決さ
Impossible...
莫迦な　吾輩の六年が…
Six years of my life...
The intellectual devices were
much more beautiful than before.
知的技術は昔より素敵になってたけど　その差が出たね
But I think you've met your match.
なに
What?
You remember your battle against me?
吾輩との対決を覚えているのか
Why would I forget about
a mystery that I solved?
僕が自分が解決した事件を忘れるわけないだろう
思い出すね
This takes me back.
We were here, pitting our
minds against each other's.
ここでお互いの頭脳を競い合った
It was the only time another
detective gave me chills.
僕が他の探偵にヒヤリとさせられたのは
後にも先にも　あれ一回限りだ
The first and the last.
I'm looking forward to
your next challenge, too.
だからね　次の勝負も期待しているよ
I hope you work really hard to
come up with something good for me.
僕の為に頑張って考えてね
I think I'll work really hard.
吾輩　頑張ろうかな
We'll need to hold a celebration
for you when we get home.
帰ったら記念日の祝宴だね
なんの
For what?
For the day the great detective
learned the truth.
名探偵が真実を知った日のさ
The day you discover that you aren't gifted,
乱歩さんは異能力者じゃなくて　観察力と推理力を…
but that you use your powers of
observation and deduction to—
僕は異能力者だ
I'm gifted.
You were laying out all
your reasoning just now.
けど先刻は推理根拠を詳らかに説明してたじゃないか
I'm gifted.
僕は異能力者
推理なんてしてない
I'm not doing any actual detective work.
今回はたまたまだ
I just got lucky this time.
I mean...
だって
You mean, what?
だって　何
I'd look stupid if I turned
out to be normal now.
今更一般人なんて恰好がつかない
No laughing.
笑うの禁止
Fine, fine.
はいはい
はいはいも禁止
Poe and Rampo
No "fine, fine" either!
The Whereabouts of the
Skyfaring Moby Dick
Is it true that we have information
we can use to defeat the Guild?
ギルドを倒せる情報が手に入ったって本当ですか
They're devising a plan inside right now.
今　奥で作戦立案中だよ
This is some amazing intel, though.
それにしても　凄い情報ですね　値千金だ
It's worth its weight in gold.
How would we make use of this to
take down the Guild at its core?
これを使って　ギルトの背骨を一撃で圧し折るとすると
Infiltrate with a bomb?
潜入から爆弾？
無理だな
No good.
通信で着水　狙撃で終わりだ
Our communications will give us away,
and we'll get shot down.
Oh, you're right.
本当だ
じゃあ　特務課突入から賢治君だと？
How about Kenji-kun from the
Gifted Special Operations Division?
無理　地上戦で痛み分け延長戦
Nope.
Leads to a stalemate in a ground battle,
and we'll be fighting overtime.
That's true.
確かに
となると敦君か
Atsushi-kun, then?
It could work, with Light Snow.
まっ　「細雪」を使えば悪くない
ですね
True.
直に掛かります
I'll get right on it.
Do we end in the mountains?
最後は山？
海だ
At sea.
Roger.
了解
はなしてよ
Let me go.
You've got gall, betraying the Guild.
ギルドを裏切るなんて思い切ったね
I wish I had your courage.
その勇気見習いたいよ
けど君の強力な異能力に　ギルドが対策してるとは思わなかった
But did you really think the Guild wouldn't
have countermeasures for your powerful ability?
知ってたわ　それくらい
I knew that much.
But I had to say I was going to be okay.
でも私は大丈夫だって云わないと
Otherwise he would never have escaped.
あいつ絶対に逃げなかったもの
Oh, man.
やれやれ　悪役組織も楽じゃないね
It's not easy being the bad guys.
So, Chief Strategist, what's the plan?
それで　作戦参謀殿　次の作戦は
Hi Ango, how're you?
は～い　安吾　元気かい
I have some good news today.
今日はよい話を持ってきたよ
We'll treat your injuries at the Agency.
その怪我　我が探偵社で治療しよう
You'll be as good as new with
Yosano-san's healing ability.
与謝野さんの治癒能力なら　ピカピカの新品に戻れるよ
And what do you want in return?
で　その見返りは
Well, one of the detectives in the Agency
was captured by the military police.
実は探偵社員が一人軍警に捕まっている
ギルドとの最終決戦の前に彼女を助けたい
We want to save her before our
grand battle with the Guild.
Ah, the killer of 35.
３５人殺しですか
危険異能力者を隔離する無人機にて拘束中と聞きました
I'm told she's being kept on an unmanned
plane used to quarantine dangerous gifteds.
確かに特務課なら　超法規的な司法取引に拠る免責も可能です
The Gifted Special Operations Division could indeed
make an extrajudicial plea to grant her immunity.
But only if the girl is truly
a member of the Agency.
ただし　その少女が本当に…
探偵社員ならば　ですが
Kyouka-chan isn't a member of the Agency?
鏡花ちゃんが探偵社員じゃない？
正確にはまだってことなんだけど
She's not yet, to be exact.
探偵社の調査員には　代々入社試験があるんだ
There's an entrance examination you need
to take in order to become a detective.
Unless you pass the test, you aren't
officially accepted as an employee.
それを通過しないと　正式な社員として認められない
敦君の時にもあったろ
Remember there was one for you, too?
Dazai-kun, I accept your offer of treatment
in exchange for my cooperation.
太宰君　治療と引き換えに協力する取引　確かに受諾しました
So tell me something.
だから一つ教えてください
正体不明の車に突っ込まれた時
When the unidentified car rammed into us,
何故か僕の緩衝嚢だけ開かなかったのですが
for some reason my airbag was
the only one that didn't deploy.
Might you know the reason?
理由をご存知ありませんかね
The entrance exam involves observing
the applicant's behaviors
入社試験は新人の行動を見て　探偵社に相応しいか閲する
to determine whether they're
suitable for the Agency.
いわば　裏審査なんだ
It's a secret test.
Whenever Kyouka-chan is in danger, she seeks
escape by hurting or doing away with someone.
鏡花ちゃんは窮地に陥ると必ず
誰かを傷つけたり　排除することで脱しようとする
それが彼女の本質なのかも
That may be her nature.
だとしたら　彼女が入社試験に合格することは…
If that's the case, she may
not pass the entrance exam.
Okay, we're here.
さぁ　着いたよ
The library?
図書館ですか？
I'm Tanizaki of the Armed Detective Agency.
武装探偵社より参りました　谷崎です
We've been waiting for you.
お待ちしておりました
Please.
どうぞ
The Agency's micro-assault
fighter, the Night Bird.
特務課の超小型強襲機「夜烏」
I'll pilot this and deliver
you to the Moby Dick.
これをボクが操縦して「白鯨」にキミを届ける
A solo infiltration?
単独潜入ですか？
The Guild is planning an
all-out ground attack.
ギルドは地上での総攻撃を計画中らしい
We'll sneak onto the Moby Dick while it's
sparsely staffed, and take control.
その隙をついて手薄な「白鯨」に潜入して　管制を奪う
I'm going to do all that by myself?
そんな大変な作戦を僕一人で
単独潜入となると
On a solo infiltration,
人選は不測の事態にも対応可能な戦闘系異能力者が望ましい
a gifted with combat abilities is preferable,
due to their ability to work under pressure.
それに君は「白鯨」の中に捕らえられて　土地勘がある
You've also been held captive aboard the Moby Dick,
so you have an idea of its structure.
加えて最悪失敗しても　君なら殺されず捕らえられるだけの可能性が高い
Furthermore, even if you do fail,
there's a good chance that you'll be captured alive.
No one is more suited for the job than you.
君以上の適任者はいないよ
Will you do it?
やってくれるかい
断れ
Turn it down.
You can't do it.
貴様には無理だ
You're the runt of the orphanage
until the day you die.
貴様は死ぬまで孤児院の愚図なのだ
I've only ever regretted
the things I didn't do.
私はしなかった事に就いてのみ　何時も後悔を感じていた
I'll do it.
やります
Entering Moby Dick visual range.
間もなく「白鯨」の視認圏に入ります
Understood.
了解
Here we go, Atsushi-kun.
行くよ　敦君
はい
Yes.
異能力
Ability: Light Snow!
Ability: Light Snow
「細雪」
The Moby Dick's sensors are disabled for just
130 seconds, while the transport helicopter docks.
「白鯨」は定期輸送ヘリを格納する１３０秒間だけ　空域センサーが切れる
We're going to hide ourselves
and close in during that time.
その隙に姿を消して接近する
What? The pilot isn't responding?
なに　パイロットからの応答がない？
はい　通信機のトラブルですかね
Perhaps some trouble with the communicator.
What the?
なんだ
Dazai-san, I'm in.
太宰さん　潜入しました
How does it look inside?
中の様子はどうだい
誰もいません　妙です
There's no one here.
Something's wrong.
みんなどこに
Where is everyone?
ほとんどが脱出した
Almost everyone evacuated.
Why do you think that might be, kid?
何故だかわかるか　小僧
Because it's the end.
終わりだからだ　この戦争もな
Of this war.
Wasn't he the one who
called down the Moby Dick?
確かあの人は「白鯨」を呼び出したギルドの異能力者
With the next attack, all of the
Guild's enemies will be turned to ash.
次の一撃でギルドの敵は凡て灰となる　この「白鯨」と共に
Along with Moby Dick.
どういうことだ
Explain!
I presume you thought you'd attack
while there aren't many people here.
大方手薄な隙を狙った心算なのであろう
But did you not suspect
that something was off
だがこのタイミングで　ギルドの主力が「白鯨」を離れる動き
when the Guild's main forces abandoned
the Moby Dick now, of all times?
不自然と思わなんだか
It would be terrible if
we became collateral.
僕達まで巻き込まれたらことだ
Stage two of the Yokohama Incineration
Operation: Moby Dick Bomb.
横浜焼却作戦の第二段階　「白鯨落とし」
これが決まれば　詛いの異能力で傷ついたこの街は　完全に破壊される
Once it happens, the city will be annihilated
thanks to the damage from the curse.
And ground zero...
そのうえ　落下地点には…
Is where the Agency and the
Mafia headquarters are.
探偵社とマフィアの拠点も含まれる
We'll crash into the ground
in less than an hour.
あと一時間足らずで地上に激突する
If Moby Dick is your special ability,
you should be able to stop its descent.
この「白鯨」があなたの異能力なら　落下を止められる筈です
You are correct that the Moby Dick
is my special ability.
確かにこの「白鯨」は儂の異能力じゃ
But 70% of its capacity has
been replaced with ordinances.
じゃが　今や内部の七割を兵器置換され
最早　儂に操作能力はない
I no longer have the ability to control it.
聞きましたか　太宰さん
Did you hear that, Dazai-san?
We need to abort the operation
and retreat immediately.
すぐ作戦を中止して避難しないと
The operation continues as planned.
作戦に変更はない
What?
はい
Take control of the Moby Dick with
your own hands and stop its descent.
君の手で「白鯨」を管制し　落下を阻止するんだ
それができるのは　今「白鯨」にいる君しかいない
You're the only one on the Moby Dick.
You're the only one who can do it.
You predicted this situation, didn't you?
この事態を予測していたんですね
As a possibility, yeah.
可能性の一つとしてね
That was part of our
reason for choosing you.
それも含めて君が適任者と判断した
Can you do it?
やれるかい
What do I need to do
to stop the descent?
落下を止めるにはどうすればいいんです
You'll have to use the control terminal.
制御端末を使うしかない
It's in the office on the highest floor.
最上階の執務室じゃ
無論　警備は厳しいがな
Though it's well guarded, of course.
Thank you.
ありがとう
If everyone's evacuated,
why are you still here?
全員避難したのなら　何故あなたは残っているのです？
If the Moby Dick is to fall on foreign land and
cause annihilation, I reckon I ought to fall with it.
この「白鯨」が異国の地に落ちて人々を皆殺しにするなら
せめて儂も共に落ちようと思う
Moby Dick was a beautiful creature
before its flesh became mechanical.
機械の体となる前の「白鯨」は美しかった
Just as the Guild was in its past.
嘗てのギルドが　そうであったように
Yes?
はい
How are you, Dazai-kun?
ご機嫌かね　太宰君
What do you want, Mori-san?
何ですか　森さん
マフィアとは探偵社の作戦を邪魔しないよう　協定を結んだ筈ですが
Didn't we establish an agreement with the
Mafia so they wouldn't obstruct our operations?
その協定だが　今　部下から連絡があってねぇ
About that agreement... I just had a
call from one of the subordinates.
It doesn't look like it'll hold.
守れそうにないのだよ
You...
お前…
I've found you, weretiger.
見つけたぞ　人虎
芥川
とんだ期待外れだ
Akutagawa!
貴様がこれほどまでに愚かとは
Episode
Twenty-Three
Rashoumon, The Tiger,
and The Last Emperor
これでは　仮令貴様を百回殺そうと　何の戦果にもならぬ
戦果だと？
戦果無き限り　あの人は僕を認めぬ
太宰さんは決して…
あの人？太宰さんて…
まさか
次回　文豪ストレイドッグス　第二十三話
羅生門と虎と最後の大君